<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://mohsenim.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mohsenim.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last Post: Time Series Forecasting - Quantile Forecasting - Quantile Loss</title>
      <link>https://mohsenim.de/blog/quantile-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohsenim.de/blog/quantile-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most common approach in time series regression analysis is symmetric modeling, where the objective is to predict the mean of the dependent variable using the least squares method. In this approach, over-predictions and under-predictions are treated equally. However, analysis can also be asymmetric, where the costs of over-prediction and under-prediction differ. This is particularly important in many real-world scenarios where over-estimation or under-estimation can result in significant losses. For example, in forecasting financial markets, any under-estimation of risks can lead to substantial financial damage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logging Datasets in Machine Learning Experiments with MLflow</title>
      <link>https://mohsenim.de/blog/mlfow-log-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohsenim.de/blog/mlfow-log-dataset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MLflow is widely recognized as a powerful tool for tracking machine learning (ML) experiments, enabling data scientists and ML experts to systematically log metrics, parameters, and models. However, its capabilities extend beyond these traditional use cases — MLflow can also be used to track datasets. Logging information about training and evaluation datasets is a critical step in enhancing the transparency and reproducibility of ML experiments. By capturing dataset details, such as versioning and splits, MLflow helps ensure that experiments can be accurately replicated and understood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure Certificates — Part 1: Azure Fundamental AZ-900</title>
      <link>https://mohsenim.de/blog/azure-ai900/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohsenim.de/blog/azure-ai900/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was offered a package of training programs covering several Microsoft Azure certificates. In a few posts, I’m going to explain each of these Azure certificates from the perspective of a data science and ML expert. The first post covers the Microsoft Azure Fundamentals certificate (AZ-900). I had access to official training by Microsoft and the learning material on learn.microsoft.com. Since the official learning material published on on learn.microsoft.com is the source for the exam, I will refer to the topics covered there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Exploration to Modeling: When ML Models Fail in Action — A Case Study</title>
      <link>https://mohsenim.de/blog/insurance-failed-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohsenim.de/blog/insurance-failed-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was asked to explore a car insurance premium dataset and predict a “fair” premium for each policyholder. The task included exploratory data analysis, feature engineering, model selection and comparison, and suggestions for model improvement. It was an interesting and insightful task, as our expectations sometimes fail and we can’t tackle the problem in a routine and straightforward way. I touch upon the exploratory analysis and model training. I will illustrate that machine learning models may not always meet our initial expectations. However, through a shift in perspective and a thorough analysis of the problem, we can still utilize their potential effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BentoML: Serving and Deploying Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://mohsenim.de/blog/bentoml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohsenim.de/blog/bentoml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BentoML is an open-source platform for packaging ML models. It effectively simplifies the productionization of ML models by offering easy-to-use built-in features.&#xA;BentoML provides a straightforward approach for packaging trained models and their associated code and dependencies into a unified distribution format called “Bento.” This platform supports various deployment options, including serving models as REST APIs, Docker containers, and batch jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/gopenai/serving-and-deploying-machine-learning-models-with-bentoml-germany-car-price-prediction-case-study-1b3968d29a38&#34;&gt;Read more &amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>https://mohsenim.de/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohsenim.de/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My contact and the address of my profile on the social websites are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mohsenim.de&#34;&gt;mohsenim.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:kontact@mohsenim.de&#34;&gt;kontakt@mohsenim.de&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@mohsenim.com&#34;&gt;contact@mohsenim.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohsenim&#34;&gt;mohsenim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GitHub: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mohsenim&#34;&gt;mohsenim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Medium: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mohsenim&#34;&gt;mohsenim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
